symphonycommerce.com 2015-03-16

# Privacy Policy | Symphony Commerce

## Privacy

## **Symphony Commerce Privacy Policy**

### Last Updated: June 30, 2014

This privacy policy applies to www.symphonycommerce.com owned and operated by Symphony Commerce (“We”, “Symphony Commerce”). This privacy policy describes how Symphony Commerce collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: www.symphonycommerce.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. We DO NOT share, sell, rent, or trade personal information with third parties except as disclosed within this privacy policy.

### How We Use the Data Collected

We reserve the right to contact you, regarding your account or any other matter regarding your use of Symphony Commerce products. You have the option to opt-out of any secondary communications such as promotional communications by clicking on “unsubscribe” on the bottom of any promotional emails. With your authorization, we may use some information collected from you to help diagnose technical problems, and improve the quality and types of services delivered. We may use and share non-identifiable aggregated usage and statistical information. We may also share information with third parties in limited circumstances including when complying with legal processes, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others or to investigate fraud, respond to a government request, prevent fraud or imminent harm, ensure security of network and services and due to violation of the terms of service. If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, we may transfer any personal information in our custody and control to the acquirer. You will be notified via email and/or a notice on our Web site of any such transaction.

### How We Collect Data

On our website, we may collect the following Personal Information from prospective clients, prospective business partners, and job applicants: name, company, email, phone number and address. We collect this information only for the purpose of contacting individuals who have identified themselves as prospects or applicants for our activities, services and job openings. We may share this information with third party service providers for email processing and related services. These third parties are prohibited from using your Personal Information for any other purpose. After registering with the site, we may use your email address to provide you with a series of ‘Ongoing Communications and Product Updates’ (see ‘Communication from the Site’). These communications are used to give you a better understanding of the site, what it offers, and how it is best utilized. As always, you have the option not to receive these types of communications (see ‘Choice and Opt-out’).

### Cookies

In order to improve the content and format of our site, Symphony Commerce uses Web site tracking services to automatically capture technical information that may be stored in our servers’ log files. This information may include, but is not limited to, user domain, the type of Internet browser being used, which of our Web pages is visited, and the amount of time spent on our site. In addition, some of Symphony Commerce’s Web pages may contain “cookies.” A cookie is a small amount of data which our Web site stores on your computer, and which we can later retrieve. The cookie cannot be read by a site other than ours. We use cookies for a number of administrative purposes, such as to store your preferences for certain kinds of information. Our cookies are tied to Personal Information to store your information and make it easier for you to use our site. We don’t share our cookies except as set out in this privacy policy, nor do we use cookies to track your behavior on other sites.

### Third Party Cookies

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company and service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company and service providers use session ID cookies (to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.).

### Clear Gifs

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see ‘Choice and Opt-out’.

### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Tell a Friend and Share Features

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about a job or to share information with a colleague or another individual, we will ask you for the individual’s name and email address. The individual will receive a one-time email with the requested information. Symphony Commerce does not store this information and the individual will not be added to our database.

### Customer Testimonials

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@symphonycommerce.com.

### Live Chat

We use live chat to assist you with sales questions and support questions from time to time. If our live chat is offline we will collect your name and email address so that we may reply to your request via email at a later time.

### Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs & community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at privacy@symphonycommerce.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Analytics/LSOs

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

### Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting

Symphony Commerce may partner with third party ad networks to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. The ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.

### Customer Service

Based upon the personal information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password as well an account manager contact information. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account.

### Service Related Announcements

We will send you service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Service-related emails are also sent confirming billing transactions, account upgrades, and account cancellations. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to cancel your account. In order to delete your Symphony Commerce account altogether, please send an email to privacy@symphonycommerce.com and Symphony Commerce support staff will process your request.

### Ongoing Communication and Product Updates

We will occasionally send you information on product enhancements, new services, and additional instruction on utilizing our services. These communications are designed to educate our users on the services offered. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the ‘Choice and Opt-out’.

### Links to Non-Symphony Commerce Web Sites and Third Parties

Symphony Commerce’s Web sites may contain links to third-party sites for your convenience and/or information. If you access those links, you will leave Symphony Commerce’s Web site and be re-directed to a third-party site. Symphony Commerce does not control those sites or the privacy practices of those third-party sites, which may differ from Symphony Commerce’s privacy practices. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party Web sites, and the personal data you choose to provide to third-party Web sites is not covered by this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any Web site or company before submitting your Personal Information to them.

### Choice/Opt-out

If you no longer wish to receive our product updates, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the “unsubscribe” instructions included in each product update email.

### What You Can Do

Your data (personal information) is yours; you can delete or export it at anytime. If you’d like your account to be deleted, please do send us an email at [privacy@symphonycommerce.com](mailto:info@symphonycommerce.com "Inquiry about Web Privacy Standards"). We may for a time, maintain a residual copy of your data in our backups.

### Information Obtained from Third Parties

You can import contacts from your Outlook or other email account address book to invite them to become members of our site. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose. If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.  Your contacts may contact us at [privacy@symphonycommerce.com ](mailto:info@symphonycommerce.com "Inquiry about Web Privacy Standards")to request that we remove this information from our database.

### Data Retention

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your Personal Information as we in good faith believe it necessary to comply with the law or with legal process including court orders or subpoenas; protect and defend our rights and property; protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web sites or ecommerce Services; or protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public.

### Security

Symphony Commerce servers are protected with generally available security technologies, including firewalls and data encryption. These technologies are designed to prevent unauthorized access, but no guarantee can be made that your information and data will be secure from intrusions and unauthorized released to third parties. The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number, national ID, personal health information) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

### Data Integrity

Symphony Commerce will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is accurate, complete, and current to its intended use. Symphony Commerce will only use Personal Information in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by you.

### Enforcement and Verification

Symphony Commerce regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or Symphony Commerce’s treatment of Personal Information by contacting us by email at [privacy@symphonycommerce.com](mailto:info@symphonycommerce.com "Inquiry about Web Privacy Standards").

### Contact Information

At any time you may contact Symphony Commerce with questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy at [privacy@symphonycommerce.com](mailto:info@symphonycommerce.com "Inquiry about Web Privacy Standards"). Written responses may also be submitted to: Symphony Commerce, Inc. Attention: General Counsel 363 Clementina Street San Francisco, CA 94103.

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

Symphony Commerce may update or replace this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes in the manner in which we treat personal information in our custody or control, or if we materially update or replace this privacy statement, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Your use of the Site or the Services after the effective date of an amendment to this Privacy Policy will be deemed to be acceptance of such amendment.

## **SYMPHONY COMMERCE SERVICES**

Symphony Commerce provides our customers with a hosted ecommerce platform and application suite of services that facilitate functionality to support the development and management of retail, wholesale and third party sales operations. The ecommerce services are not a part of our corporate web site. Symphony Commerce serves as a Data Processor for our customers who use these services. More specifically, Symphony Commerce does not own the information that is submitted to our customers’ websites. The information that is submitted to a Web site of one of our customers will be subject to that customer’s privacy policy. The following information discloses how information is submitted to these websites and how Symphony Commerce will handle the information for our customers who are the owners of this data.

### Ecommerce Customer Web Visitors

Symphony Commerce processes Personal Information about a visitor to our customers’ websites (“Visitors”) only when the Visitor chooses to provide such information. On certain pages, for example, a Visitor may be required to provide his/her personal information such as his/her name, address, phone number and e-mail address in order to complete a transaction or perform a requested service.

### Employees

Symphony Commerce employees may process Personal Information from our customers’ employees for, among other things, application access and authentication.

### Onward Transfer

We may contract with third-party providers to perform certain functions on behalf of our customers to enhance our existing product and service offerings, such as product and service support. These third parties may have access to Visitors’ Personal Information as necessary to permit them to perform their functions. They are bound by confidentiality agreements or similar contractual restrictions with respect to any information that is provided to them and they are prohibited from using the information for other purposes.

### Cookies

In order to improve the content and format of our platform and applications, our ecommerce Services use Web site tracking software to automatically capture technical information that is then stored in our servers’ log files. This information may include, but is not limited to, user domain, the type of Internet browser being used, which of our customers’ Web pages are visited, and the amount of time spent on our customers’ sites. Our customers’ website pages may contain “cookies.” A cookie is a small amount of data which a Web site stores on a Visitor’s computer, and which we or our customers can later retrieve. The cookie cannot be read by a site other than ours or our customer’s. We and our customers use cookies for a number of administrative purposes, such as to store Visitors’ preferences for certain kinds of information. Any use of cookies by our customers will be governed by our customers’ privacy policies. Visitors can monitor use of cookies on their computers by setting their Web browser to inform them when cookies are set, or Visitors can prevent the cookies from being set entirely.

### Security

To protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of Visitors’ Personal Information that is processed by our services, Symphony Commerce utilizes a variety of industry standard physical and logical access controls, firewalls, intrusion detection/prevention systems, network and database monitoring, and backup systems. We use SSL encrypted sessions when processing or transferring sensitive data through platform and applications. We limit access to Visitors’ Personal Information and data to those persons who have a specific business purpose for maintaining and processing such information. Symphony Commerce employees who have been granted physical access to a Visitor’s Personal Information have been made aware of their responsibilities to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of that information and have been provided training and instruction on how to do so.

### Access

Symphony Commerce will support our customers in taking reasonable steps to ensure that Visitor’s Personal Information is accurate, complete, and current to its intended use. We provide our customers with reasonable access to the Personal Information that they provide to us, as well as the ability to review, correct or request the deletion of such information.

### Data Retention

We and our customers may retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services and as otherwise set forth in our respective customer’s privacy policy. We and our customers may retain and use your information as reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our rights and as otherwise set forth in our respective customer’s privacy policy.

### Links to Non-Symphony Commerce Web Sites and Third Parties

Symphony Commerce Customer Web sites may contain links to third-party sites for Visitors’ convenience and/or information. If a Visitor accesses those links, he/she will leave the Symphony Commerce customer’s website and be re-directed to a third-party site. Symphony Commerce does not control those sites or the privacy practices of those third-party sites, which may differ from Symphony Commerce’s privacy practices and those of our customer. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party Web sites, and the personal data Visitors choose to provide to third-party Web sites is not covered by this Privacy Policy. We encourage Visitors to review the privacy policy of any Web site or company before submitting their Personal Information to it.
